<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
        <!--
        Es wir hier explizit auf einen DocType verzichten um diese Datei in der Transformation nutzen zu koennen, ohne das sie gegen die properties.dtd geprüft wird.
        Wenn die Datei als Properties gezogen wird, wird ein DocType zur Laufzeit eingetragen.
        -->
<properties>
    <entry key="espd.gui.about">About</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.all.selection.switch">?: Global indication for all selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.app.environment">Dear user, you are using our testing environment. Please use</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.app.subtitle">Service to fill out and reuse the ESPD</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.app.title">European Single Procurement Document (ESPD)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.back.to.main">Back to main page</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.cancel">Cancel</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.click.here">click here</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.contact">Contact</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.contact.header">Contact</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.contact.info">European Commission Directorate General Internal Market, Industry, Entrepreneurship and SMEs Avenue d'Auderghem 45 / Oudergemselaan 45 B-1049 Brussels Belgium</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.cookies">Cookies</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.correct.errors">You need to correct the errors before you can continue.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.city">City:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.confirm.email">Confirm e-mail:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.confirm.telephone">Confirm Telephone:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.contact.details.ca">Identity of the procurer</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.contact.person">Contact Person:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.correct.errors">You need to correct the errors before you can continue.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.country">Country:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.email">E-mail:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.fax">Fax</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.file.ref.ca">File reference number attributed by the contracting authority or contracting entity (if applicable):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.header">Part I: Information concerning the procurement procedure and the contracting authority or contracting entity</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.info.procedure">Type of Procedure</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.info.procurement.proc">Information about the procurement procedure</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.info.pub">Information about publication</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.name">Official name:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.nat.regnum">National registration number (if known):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.official.journal.alert">In case publication of a notice in the Official Journal of the European Union is not required, please give other information allowing the procurement procedure to be unequivocally identified (e. g. reference of a publication at national level)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.ojs.label">Notice number in the OJS:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.ojs.url">OJS URL</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.postcode">Postcode:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.procurer.name">Title:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.street.and. num">Street and number:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.ted.reception.id">Received notice number</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.telephone">Telephone:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.title.or.short.desc">Short description:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.to.be.filled.alert">For procurement procedures in which a call for competition has been published in the Official Journal of the European Union, the information required under Part I will be automatically retrieved, provided that the electronic ESPD-service  is used to generate and fill in the ESPD. Reference of the relevant notice  published in the Official Journal of the European Union:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part1.website">Website (if applicable):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.grounds.criminal.conv">Grounds Relating to Criminal Convictions</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.header">Part III: Exclusion grounds</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.insolvency.conflicts">Grounds relating to insolvency, conflicts of interests or professional misconduct</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.concl.statements">Part VI: Concluding statements</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.concl.statements.signature">Date, place and, where required or necessary, signature(s):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.concl.statements.text">The undersigned formally declare that the information stated under Parts II - V above is accurate and correct and that it has been set out in full awareness of the consequences of serious misrepresentation.&lt;br&gt;The undersigned formally declare to be able, upon request and without delay, to provide the certificates and other forms of documentary evidence referred to, except where:&lt;br&gt;a) The contracting authority or contracting entity has the possibility of obtaining the supporting documentation concerned directly by accessing a national database in any Member State that is available free of charge (on condition that the economic operator has provided the necessary information (web address, issuing authority or body, precise reference of the documentation) allowing the contracting authority or contracting entity to do so. Where required, this must be accompanied by the relevant  consent to such access), or&lt;br&gt;b) As of 18 October 2018 at the latest (depending on the national implementation of the second subparagraph of Article 59(5) of Directive 2014/24/EU), the contracting authority or contracting entity already possesses the documentation concerned.&lt;br&gt;The undersigned formally consent to [identify the contracting authority or contracting entity as set out in Part I, Section A], gaining access to documents supporting the information, which has been provided in [identify the Part/Section/Point(s) concerned] of this European Single Procurement Document for the purposes of [identify the procurement procedure: (summary description, reference of publication in the Official Journal of the European Union, reference number)].</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.export">Save</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.export.content">You can now click on 'Export' to download and save the ESPD file on your computer. Contracting authorities must ensure that this ESPD file is available to the economic operators alongside the other tender documents.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.header">Finish</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.reduction">Part V: Reduction of the number of qualified candidates</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.reduction.question">The economic operator declares that:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.text.eo.declares.that">If some of these certificates or forms of documentary evidence are available electronically, please indicate for each:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.title.eo.declares.that">It meets the objective and non discriminatory criteria or rules to be applied in order to limit the number of candidates in the following way: In case certain certificates or other forms of documentary evidence are required, please indicate for each whether the economic operator has the required documents:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part5.toptext">The economic operator should only provide information where the contracting authority or contracting entity has specified the objective and non discriminatory criteria or rules to be applied in order to limit the number of candidates that will be invited to tender or to conduct a dialogue. This information, which can be accompanied by requirements concerning the (types of) certificates or forms of documentary evidence, if any, to be produced, is set out in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice. For restricted procedures, competitive procedures with negotiation, competitive dialogue procedures and innovation partnerships only:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.alert">Contracting authorities must indicate which selection criteria will be applied by 'ticking' the checkbox placed before the relevant criterion.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.economic.and.financial.standing">B: Economic and financial standing</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.header">Part IV: Selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.quality.assurance">D: Quality assurance schemes and environmental management standards</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.suitability">A: Suitability</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.technical.professional.ability">C: Technical and professional ability</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.add.complete.missing">In addition, please complete the missing information in Part IV, Sections A, B, C or D as the case may be ONLY if this is required in the relevant notice or procurement documents</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.all.selection.covered">d) Does the registration or certification cover all of the required selection criteria?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.another.vat">If no VAT number is applicable, please indicate another national identification number, if required and applicable</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.answer.following.parts">Please answer the remaining parts of this Section, Sections B and, where relevant, C of this Part, complete Part V, where applicable, and, in any case, fill in and sign Part VI.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.birth.date">Date of birth</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.birth.place">Place of birth</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.cert.e.avaliable">b) If the certificate of registration or certification is available electronically, please state:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.contact.person">Contact person or persons:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.detinfo.of.represent">If needed, please provide detailed information on the representation (its forms, extent, purpose ...):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.disworkers.details">If required, please specify which category or categories of disabled or disadvantaged workers the employees concerned belong to?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.doc.e.avaliable">If the relevant documentation is available electronically, please indicate:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.email">E-mail:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.ensure.others.espd">Please ensure that the others concerned  provide a separate ESPD form.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.eo.approved.cert">If applicable, is the economic operator registered on an official list of approved economic operators or does it have an equivalent certificate (e.g. under a national (pre)qualification system)?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.eo.group.role">a) Please indicate the role of the economic operator in the group (leader, responsible for specific tasks...):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.eo.has.cert.soc">e) Will the economic operator be able to provide a certificate with regard to the payment of social security contributions and taxes or provide information enabling the contracting authority or contracting entity to obtaining it directly by accessing a national database in any Member State that is available free of charge?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.eo.rely.other.entities">Does the economic operator rely on the capacities of other entities in order to meet the selection criteria set out under Part IV and the criteria and rules (if any) set out under Part V below?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.first.name">First name</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.header">Part II: Information concerning the economic operator</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.if.proc.reserved">Only in case the procurement is reserved: is the economic operator a sheltered workshop, a 'social business'  or will it provide for the performance of the contract in the context of sheltered employment programmes?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.info.eo">A: Information about the economic operator</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.info.reliance">C: Information about reliance on the capacities of other entities</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.info.respresent">B: Information about representatives of the economic operator</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.information.subcontractors">D: Information concerning subcontractors on whose capacity the economic operator does not rely</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.information.subcontractors.description">If yes and in so far as known, please list the proposed subcontractors:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.information.subcontractors.footer">If the contracting authority or contracting entity explicitly requests this information in addition to the information under Part I, please provide the information required under  Sections A and B of this Part  and Part III for each of the (categories of) subcontractors concerned.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.information.subcontractors.header">(Section to be filled-in only if this information is explicitly required by the contracting authority or contracting entity.)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.information.subcontractors.title">Does the economic operator intend to subcontract any share of the contract to third parties?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.internet.addr.if.exists">Internet address (web address) (if applicable):</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.is.eo.proc.together">Is the economic operator participating in the procurement procedure together with others?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.is.eo.sized">Is the economic operator a Micro, a Small or a Medium-Sized Enterprise?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.is.eo.sized.tooltip">Cf. Commission Recommendation of 6 May 2003 concerning the definition of micro, small and medium sized enterprises, (OJ L 124 of 20.5.2003, p. 36). This information is required for statistical purposes only. Micro enterprises: enterprise which employs fewer than 10 persons and whose annual turnover and/or annual balance sheet total does not exceed EUR 2 million. Small enterprises: an enterprise which employs fewer than 50 persons and whose annual turnover and/or annual balance sheet total does not exceed EUR 10 million; Medium enterprises, enterprises which are neither micro nor small and which employ fewer than 250 persons and which have an annual turnover not exceeding EUR 50 million, and/or an annual balance sheet total not exceeding EUR 43 million</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.last.name">Last name</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.lots.concerned">Where applicable, indication of the lot(s) for which the economic operator wishes to tender:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.name">Name:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.name.part.group">c) Where applicable, name of the participating group:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.other.eo.part">b) Please identify the other economic operators participating in the procurement procedure together:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.percentage.disworkers">What is the corresponding percentage of disabled or disadvantaged workers?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.person.empowered">Where applicable, please indicate the name(s) and address(es) of the person(s) empowered to represent the economic operator for the purposes of this procurement procedure:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.pos.act.in.capacity">Position/Acting in the capacity of:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.postal.adress">Postal address:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.provide.regnumber">a) Please provide the name of the list or certificate and the relevant registration or certification number, if applicable:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.ref.for.cert">c) Please state the references on which the registration or certification is based, and, where applicable, the classification obtained in the official list:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.separate.espd.sections.a.b">Please provide a separate ESPD form setting out the information required under Sections A and B of this Part and Part III for each of the entities concerned, duly filled in and signed by the entities concerned.<p/>Please note that this should also include any technicians or technical bodies, not belonging directly to the economic operator's undertaking, especially those responsible for quality control and, in the case of public works contracts, the technicians or technical bodies upon whom the economic operator can call in order to carry out the work.<p/>Insofar as it is relevant for the specific capacity or capacities on which the economic operator relies, please include the information under Parts IV and V for each of the entities concerned.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.telephone">Telephone:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2.vat">VAT number, if applicable:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part2sel.alert">The economic operator should only provide information where the selection criteria concerned have been required by the contracting authority or contracting entity in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.amount">Amount</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.amount.concerned">Amount concerned</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.average.turnover">Average turnover</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.code">Reference/Code</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.country.member.state">Country or Member State concerned</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.date">Date</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.date.of.conviction">Date of conviction</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.date.of.conviction.or.decision">Please indicate the date of conviction or decision</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.decision.final.and.binding">If this breach of obligations was established through a judicial or administrative decision, was this decision final and binding?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.description">Description</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.do.you.allow.checks">Do you allow checks?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.end.date">End date</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.main.breaching.obligations">Article 57(4) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following reasons for exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.eo.main.breaching.obligations">Article 57(4) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following reasons for exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.main.purely.national">Do the purely national grounds of exclusion, which are specified in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents, apply?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.grounds.criminal.conv.main.title">Article 57(1) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following reasons for exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.eo.grounds.criminal.conv.main.title">Article 57(1) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following reasons for exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.payment.taxes.main.title">Article 57(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following reasons for exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.eo.payment.taxes.main.title">Article 57(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following reasons for exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.agreement.economic">Has the economic operator entered into agreements with other economic operators aimed at distorting competition?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.arrangement.creditors">Is the economic operator in arrangement with creditors? This information needs not be given if exclusion of economic operators in this case has been made mandatory under the applicable national law without any possibility of derogation where the economic operator is nevertheless able to perform the contract.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.bankrupt">Is the economic operator bankrupt? This information needs not be given if exclusion of economic operators in this case has been made mandatory under the applicable national law without any possibility of derogation where the economic operator is nevertheless able to perform the contract.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.breaching.obligations.environmental">Has the economic operator, to its knowledge, breached its obligations in the field of environmental law? As referred to for the purposes of this procurement in national law, in the relevant notice or the procurement documents or in Article 18(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.breaching.obligations.labour">Has the economic operator, to its knowledge, breached its obligations in the field of labour law? As referred to for the purposes of this procurement in national law, in the relevant notice or the procurement documents or in Article 18(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.breaching.obligations.social">Has the economic operator, to its knowledge, breached its obligations in the field of social law? As referred to for the purposes of this procurement in national law, in the relevant notice or the procurement documents or in Article 18(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.child.labour">Has the economic operator itself or any person who is a member of its administrative, management or supervisory body or has powers of representation, decision or control therein been the subject of a conviction by final judgment for child labour and other forms of trafficking in human beings, by a conviction rendered at the most five years ago or in which an exclusion period set out directly in the conviction continues to be applicable? As defined in Article 2 of Directive 2011/36/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 5 April 2011 on preventing and combating trafficking in human beings and protecting its victims, and replacing Council Framework Decision 2002/629/JHA (OJ L 101, 15.4.2011, p. 1).</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.conflict.interest">Is the economic operator aware of any conflict of interest, as indicated in national law, the relevant notice or the procurement documents due to its participation in the procurement procedure?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.corruption">Has the economic operator itself or any person who is a member of its administrative, management or supervisory body or has powers of representation, decision or control therein been the subject of a conviction by final judgment for corruption, by a conviction rendered at the most five years ago or in which an exclusion period set out directly in the conviction continues to be applicable? As defined in Article 3 of the Convention on the fight against corruption involving officials of the European Communities or officials of Member States of the European Union, OJ C 195, 25.6.1997, p. 1, and in Article 2(1) of Council Framework Decision 2003/568/JHA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (OJ L 192, 31.7.2003, p. 54). This exclusion ground also includes corruption as defined in the national law of the contracting authority (contracting entity) or the economic operator.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.early.termination">Has the economic operator experienced that a prior public contract, a prior contract with a contracting entity or a prior concession contract was terminated early, or that damages or other comparable sanctions were imposed in connection with that prior contract?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.fraud">Has the economic operator itself or any person who is a member of its administrative, management or supervisory body or has powers of representation, decision or control therein been the subject of a conviction by final judgment for fraud, by a conviction rendered at the most five years ago or in which an exclusion period set out directly in the conviction continues to be applicable? Within the meaning of Article 1 of the Convention on the protection of the European Communities' financial interests (OJ C 316, 27.11.1995, p. 48).</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.grounds.criminal.conv">Has the economic operator itself or any person who is a member of its administrative, management or supervisory body or has powers of representation, decision or control therein been the subject of a conviction by final judgment for participation in a criminal organisation, by a conviction rendered at the most five years ago or in which an exclusion period set out directly in the conviction continues to be applicable? As defined in Article 2 of Council Framework Decision 2008/841/JHA of 24 October 2008 on the fight against organised crime (OJ L 300, 11.11.2008, p. 42).</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.guilty.misconduct">Is the economic operator guilty of grave professional misconduct? Where applicable, see definitions in national law, the relevant notice or the procurement documents.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.guilty.misinterpretation">Can the economic operator confirm that:<p/>a) It has been guilty of serious misrepresentation in supplying the information required for the verification of the absence of grounds for exclusion or the fulfilment of the selection criteria,<p/>b) It has withheld such information,<p/>c) It has not been able, without delay, to submit the supporting documents required by a contracting authority or contracting entity, and<p/>d) It has undertaken to unduly influence the decision making process of the contracting authority or contracting entity, to obtain confidential information that may confer upon it undue advantages in the procurement procedure or to negligently provide misleading information that may have a material influence on decisions concerning exclusion, selection or award?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.insolvency">Is the economic operator the subject of insolvency or winding-up? This information needs not be given if exclusion of economic operators in this case has been made mandatory under the applicable national law without any possibility of derogation where the economic operator is nevertheless able to perform the contract.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.involvement">Has the economic operator or an undertaking related to it advised the contracting authority or contracting entity or otherwise been involved in the preparation of the procurement procedure?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.liquidator">Are the assets of the economic operator being administered by a liquidator or by the court? This information needs not be given if exclusion of economic operators in this case has been made mandatory under the applicable national law without any possibility of derogation where the economic operator is nevertheless able to perform the contract.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.money.laundering">Has the economic operator itself or any person who is a member of its administrative, management or supervisory body or has powers of representation, decision or control therein been the subject of a conviction by final judgment for money laundering or terrorist financing, by a conviction rendered at the most five years ago or in which an exclusion period set out directly in the conviction continues to be applicable? As defined in Article 1 of Directive 2005/60/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 26 October 2005 on the prevention of the use of the financial system for the purpose of money laundering and terrorist financing (OJ L 309, 25.11.2005, p. 15).</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.national.bankruptcy">Is the economic operator in in any analogous situation like bankruptcy arising from a similar procedure under national laws and regulations? This information needs not be given if exclusion of economic operators in this case has been made mandatory under the applicable national law without any possibility of derogation where the economic operator is nevertheless able to perform the contract.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.payment.social.security">Has the economic operator breached its obligations relating to the payment social security contributions, both in the country in which it is established and in Member State of the contracting authority or contracting entity if other than the country of establishment?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.payment.taxes">Has the economic operator breached its obligations relating to the payment of taxes, both in the country in which it is established and in Member State of the contracting authority or contracting entity if other than the country of establishment?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.purely.national">Other exclusion grounds that may be foreseen in the national legislation of the contracting authority's or contracting entity's Member State. Has the economic operator breached its obligations relating to the purely national grounds of exclusion, which are specified in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.suspended.business">Are the business activities of the economic operator suspended? This information needs not be given if exclusion of economic operators in this case has been made mandatory under the applicable national law without any possibility of derogation where the economic operator is nevertheless able to perform the contract.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.text.terrorist">Has the economic operator itself or any person who is a member of its administrative, management or supervisory body or has powers of representation, decision or control therein been the subject of a conviction by final judgment for terrorist offences or offences linked to terrorist activities, by a conviction rendered at the most five years ago or in which an exclusion period set out directly in the conviction continues to be applicable? As defined in Articles 1 and 3 of Council Framework Decision of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (OJ L 164, 22.6.2002, p. 3). This exclusion ground also includes inciting or aiding or abetting or attempting to commit an offence, as referred to in Article 4 of that Framework Decision.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.agreement.economic">Agreements with other economic operators aimed at distorting competition</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.arrangement.creditors">Arrangement with creditors</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.bankrupt">Bankruptcy</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.eo.bankrupt.title">Is your organisation bankrupt, or the subject of insolvency or winding-up proceedings, or in an arrangement with creditors, or in any analogous situation arising from a similar procedure under national laws and regulations?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.breaching.obligations.environmental">Breaching of obligations in the field of environmental law</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.breaching.obligations.environmental.eo">Breaching of obligations in the field of environmental law</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.breaching.obligations.labour">Breaching of obligations in the fields of labour law</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.breaching.obligations.social">Breaching of obligations in the field of social law</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.child.labour">Child labour and other forms of trafficking in human beings</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.conflict.interest">Conflict of interest due to its participation in the procurement procedure</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.conflict.interest.eo">Has your organisation any conflict of interest due to its participation in the procurement procedure?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.corruption">Corruption</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.early.termination">Early termination, damages or other comparable sanctions</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.fraud">Fraud</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.grounds.criminal.conv">Participation in a criminal organisation</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.guilty.misconduct">Guilty of grave professional misconduct</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.guilty.misconduct.eo">Has your organisation found guilty of grave professional misconduct?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.guilty.misinterpretation">Guilty of misinterpretation, withheld information, unable to provide required documents and obtained confidential information of this procedure</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.insolvency">Insolvency</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.involvement">Direct or indirect involvement in the preparation of this procurement procedure</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.involvement.eo">Has your organisation or an undertaking related to it advised the contracting authority or otherwise been involved in the preparation of the procurement procedure?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.liquidator">Assets being administered by liquidator</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.money.laundering">Money laundering or terrorist financing</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.national.bankruptcy">Analogous situation like bankruptcy under national law</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.payment.social.security">Payment of social security</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.payment.taxes">Payment of taxes</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.purely.national">Purely national exclusion grounds</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.suspended.business">Business activities are suspended</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.eu.title.terrorist">Terrorist offences or offences linked to terrorist activities</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.eu.guilty.misconduct.eo.tooltip">Where applicable, see definitions in national law, the relevant notice or the procurement documents</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.explain.certificates.independent.environmental.description">If not, please explain why and specify which other means of proof concerning the environmental management systems or standards can be provided:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.explain.certificates.independent.quality.description">If not, please explain why and specify which other means of proof concerning the quality assurance scheme can be provided:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.explain.supply.contracts.quality.description">If not, please explain why and state which other means of proof can be provided:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.information.available.electronically">Is this information available at no cost to the authorities from an EU Member State database?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.issuer">Issuer</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.length.period.exclusion">Length of the period of exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.number">Number</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.number.of.years">Number of years</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.other.than.judicial.or.administrative.decision">Has this breach of obligations been established by means other than a judicial or administrative decision?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.please.describe.them">Please describe them</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.please.specify">Please specify</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.ratio">Ratio</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.reason">Reason</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.reasons.nevertheless.contract">Indicate reasons for being able nevertheless to perform the contract</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.recipients">Recipients</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.ca.declares.that">Concerning the selection criteria the contracting authority declares that</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.ca.economic.article">Article 58(3) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.declares.that.tooltip">The economic operator should only fill in this field in case the contracting authority or contracting entity has indicated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice that the economic operator can limit itself to filling in this point of Part IV without having to  fill in Part IV, Sections A, B, C or D</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.average.yearly.turnover.description">Its average yearly turnover for the number of years required in the relevant notice, the procurement documents or the ESPD is as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.average.yearly.turnover.main">Average yearly turnover</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.financial.ratio.description">Concerning the financial ratios specified in the relevant notice, the procurement documents or the ESPD, the economic operator declares that the actual values for the required ratios are as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.financial.ratio.main">Financial ratio</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.financial.standing.article.tooltip">The economic operator should only provide information where the selection criteria concerned have been required by the contracting authority or contracting entity in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.general.yearly.turnover.description">Its general yearly turnover for the number of financial years required in the relevant notice, the procurement documents or the ESPD is as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.general.yearly.turnover.main">General yearly turnover</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.other.financial.requirements.description">Concerning the other economic or financial requirements, if any, that may have been specified in the relevant notice or the procurement documents, the economic operator declares that:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.other.financial.requirements.main">Other economic or financial requirements</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.professional.risk.insurance.description">The insured amount in its professional risk indemnity insurance is the following:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.professional.risk.insurance.main">Professional risk indemnity insurance</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.setup.eo.description">In case the information concerning turnover (general or specific) is not available for the entire period required, please state the date on which the economic operator was set up or started trading:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.setup.eo.main">Set up of economic operator</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.specific.average.turnover.description">Its specific average yearly turnover in the business area covered by the contract for the number of years required in the relevant notice, the procurement documents or the ESPD is as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.specific.average.turnover.main">Specific average turnover</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.specific.yearly.turnover.description">Its specific yearly turnover in the business area covered by the contract for the number of financial years required in the relevant notice, the procurement documents or the ESPD is as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.economic.specific.yearly.turnover.main">Specific yearly turnover</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.declares.that">Concerning the selection criteria the economic operator declares that</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.declares.that.tooltip">The economic operator should only fill in this field in case the contracting authority or contracting entity has indicated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice that the economic operator can limit itself to filling in this point of Part IV without having to  fill in Part IV, Sections A, B, C or D</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.economic.article">Article 58(3) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.economic.article.tooltip">The economic operator should only provide information where the selection criteria concerned have been required by the contracting authority or contracting entity in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.economic.enrolement.description">It is enrolled in the relevant professional or trade registers kept in the Member State of its establishment</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.economic.enrolement.main">Enrolment in professional or in trade registers</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.economic.service.contracts.description">Is a particular authorisation or membership of a particular organisation needed in order to be able to perform the service in question in the country of establishment of the economic operator?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.economic.service.contracts.main">For service contracts: Need of authorisation or membership</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.satisfies.all.criteria">It satisfies all the required selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.suitability.article">Article 58(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.suitability.article.tooltip">The economic operator should only provide information where the selection criteria concerned have been required by the contracting authority or contracting entity in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.suitability.enrolment.description">It is enrolled in the relevant professional or trade registers kept in the Member State of its establishment</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.suitability.enrolment.main">Enrolment in professional or in trade registers</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.suitability.service.contracts.description">Is a particular authorisation or membership of a particular organisation needed in order to be able to perform the service in question in the country of establishment of the economic operator?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.eo.suitability.service.contracts.main">For service contracts: Need of authorisation or membership</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.quality.assurance.article">Article 62(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.quality.assurance.tooltip">The economic operator should only provide information where the selection criteria concerned have been required by the contracting authority or contracting entity in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.quality.certificate.independent.bodies.environmental.description">Will the economic operator be able to produce certificates drawn up by independent bodies attesting that the economic operator complies with the required environmental management systems or standards?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.quality.certificate.independent.bodies.environmental.main">Certificates by independent bodies about environmental management systems or standards</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.quality.certificate.independent.bodies.quality.description">Will the economic operator be able to produce certificates drawn up by independent bodies attesting that the economic operator complies with the required quality assurance standards, including accessibility for disabled persons?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.quality.certificate.independent.bodies.quality.main">Certificates by independent bodies about quality assurance standards</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.satisfies.all.criteria">It satisfies all the required selection criteria indicated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.suitability.article">Article 58(2) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.suitability.article.tooltip">The economic operator should only fill in this field in case the contracting authority or contracting entity has indicated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice that the economic operator can limit itself to filling in Section ï¡ of Part IV without having to fill in any other Section of Part IV:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.enrolment.professional.register.description">It is enrolled in relevant professional registers kept in the Member State of its establishment as described in Annex XI of Directive 2014/24/EU; economic operators from certain Member States may have to comply with other requirements set out in that Annex.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.enrolment.professional.register.main">Enrolment in a relevant professional register</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.enrolment.trade.register.description">It is enrolled in trade registers kept in the Member State of its establishment as described in Annex XI of Directive 2014/24/EU; economic operators from certain Member States may have to comply with other requirements set out in that Annex.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.enrolment.trade.register.main">Enrolment in a trade register</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.service.contracts.auth.description">Is a particular authorisation of a particular organisation needed in order to be able to perform the service in question in the country of establishment of the economic operator?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.service.contracts.auth.main">For service contracts: authorisation of particular organisation needed</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.service.contracts.membership.description">Is a particular membership of a particular organisation needed in order to be able to perform the service in question in the country of establishment of the economic operator?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.suitability.service.contracts.membership.main">For service contracts: membership of particular organisation needed</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.allowance.of.checks.description">For complex products or services to be supplied or, exceptionally, for products or services which are required for a special purpose: The economic operator will allow checks to be conducted on the production capacities or the technical capacity of the economic operator and, where necessary, on the means of study and research which are available to it and on the quality control measures? The check is to be performed by the contracting authority or, in case the latter consents to this, on its behalf by a competent official body of the country in which the supplier or service provider is established.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.allowance.of.checks.main">Allowance of checks</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.average.annual.manpower.description">The economic operator's average annual manpower for the last three years were as follows:the bid (company to authority).Chr(92)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.average.annual.manpower.main">Average annual manpower</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.educational.professional.qualifications.description">The following educational and professional qualifications are held by the service provider or the contractor itself, and/or (depending on the requirements set out in the relevant notice or the procurement documents) by its managerial staff.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.educational.professional.qualifications.main">Educational and professional qualifications</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.environment.management.features.description">The economic operator will be able to apply the following environmental management measures when performing the contract:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.environment.management.features.main">Environmental management measures</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.number.managerial.staff.description">The economic operator's number of managerial staff for the last three years were as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.number.managerial.staff.main">Number of managerial staff</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.technical.professional.ability.article">Article 58(4) of Directive 2014/24/EU sets out the following selection criteria</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part4.crit.selection.technical.professional.ability.article.tooltip">The economic operator should only provide information where the selection criteria concerned have been required by the contracting authority or contracting entity in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents referred to in the notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.service.contracts.performance.services.description">For public service contracts only: During the reference period, the economic operator has provided the following main services of the type specified. Contracting authorities may require up to three years and allow experience dating from more than three years.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.service.contracts.performance.services.main">For service contracts: performance of services of the specified type</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.study.research.facilities.description">It uses the following study and research facilities:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.study.research.facilities.main">Study and research facilities</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.subcontracting.proportion.description">The economic operator intends possibly to subcontract the following proportion (i.e. percentage) of the contract. Please note that if the economic operator has decided to subcontract a part of the contract and relies on the subcontractor's capacities to perform that part, then please fill in a separate ESPD for such subcontractors, see Part II, Section C above.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.subcontracting.proportion.main">Subcontracting proportion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.chain.management.description">It will be able to apply the following supply chain management and tracking systems when performing the contract:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.chain.management.main">Supply chain management</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.certificate.quality.description">Can the economic operator provide the required certificates drawn up by official quality control institutes or agencies of recognised competence attesting the conformity of products clearly identified by references to the technical specifications or standards, which are set out in the relevant notice or the procurement documents?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.certificate.quality.main">For supply contracts: certificates by quality control institutes</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.performance.deliveries.description">For public supply contracts only: During the reference period, the economic operator has delivered the following principal deliveries of the type specified. Contracting authorities may require up to three years and allow experience dating from more than three years.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.performance.deliveries.main">For supply contracts: performance of deliveries of the specified type</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.with.ca.description">For public supply contracts: The economic operator will supply the required samples, descriptions or photographs of the products to be supplied and will provide certifications of authenticity where applicable.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.with.ca.main">For supply contracts: samples, descriptions or photographs with certification of authenticity</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.without.ca.description">For public supply contracts: The economic operator will supply the required samples, descriptions or photographs of the products to be supplied, which do not need to be accompanied by certifications of authenticity.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.supply.contracts.without.ca.main">For supply contracts: samples, descriptions or photographs without certification of authenticity</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.technical.facilities.measures.description">It uses the following technical facilities and measures for ensuring quality and its study and research facilities are as follows:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.technical.facilities.measures.main">Technical facilities and measures for ensuring quality</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.technicians.technical.bodies.description">It can call upon the following technicians or technical bodies, especially those responsible for quality control. For technicians or technical bodies not belonging directly to the economic operator's undertaking but on whose capacities the economic operator relies as set out under Part II, Section C, separate ESPD forms must be filled in.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.technicians.technical.bodies.main">Technicians or technical bodies for quality control</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.tools.plant.description">The following tools, plant or technical equipment will be available to it for performing the contract:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.tools.plant.main">Tools, plant or technical equipment</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.work.contracts.performance.works.description">For public works contracts only: During the reference period, the economic operator has performed the following works of the specified type. Contracting authorities may require up to five years and allow experience dating from more than five years.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.work.contracts.performance.works.main">For works contracts: performance of works of the specified type</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.work.contracts.technicians.description">In the case of public works contracts, the economic operator will be able to call on the following technicians or technical bodies to carry out the work:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.selection.technical.work.contracts.technicians.main">For works contracts: technicians or technical bodies to carry out the work</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.start.date">Start date</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.taken.self.cleaning.measures">Have you taken measures to demonstrate your reliability (Chr(34)Self-CleaningChr(34))</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.taxes.eo.fulfilled.obligations">Has the economic operator fulfilled its obligations by paying or entering into a binding arrangement with a view to paying the taxes or social security contributions due, including, where applicable, any interest accrued or fines?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.taxes.length.period.of.exclusion">In case of a conviction, insofar as established directly therein, the length of the period of exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.taxes.means.description">Please describe which means were used</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.grounds.criminal.conv.top.title">A: Grounds relating to criminal convictions</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.top.grounds.payment.taxes.title">B: Grounds relating to the payment of taxes or social security contributions</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.insolvency.conflicts.top.title">C: Grounds relating to insolvency, conflicts of interests or professional misconduct</entry>
    <entry key="espd.part3.crit.purely.national.top.title">D: Purely national exclusion grounds</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.url">URL</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.who.convicted">Who has been convicted</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.year">Year</entry>
    <entry key="espd.crit.your.answer">Your answer?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.download.as">Download as</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.download.pdf">PDF format</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.download.xml">XML format</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.download.zip">Both formats</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.ec">European Commission</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.404">No ECERTIS data</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.issued">Issued By</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.language">Language</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.loading">Loading from ECERTIS...</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.no.evidences">No evidences</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.error.ted.notice.not.supported">The uploaded file is a notice and not an ESPD, therefore it cannot be used with this service</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.espd">European Single Procurement Document</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.espd.upload.error">The uploaded file could not be correctly read. Is it a valid ESPD Request or Response?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.espd.upload.request.error">The uploaded file could not be correctly read. Is it a valid ESPD Request?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.espd.upload.response.error">The uploaded file could not be correctly read. Is it a valid ESPD Response?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.europa">Europa</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.expire.reminder.message">You have not done any action in the ESPD service for almost one hour. Please save the eESPD to make sure that you do not loose data. You can import (reuse) your eESPD at any time to continue working.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.export">Save</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.faq.leaflet">FAQ leaflet</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.faq.text.answers">If you are interested in the answers to the most frequently asked questions about the ESPD, please have a look at the</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.faq.text.more.info">For more information on ESPD, please</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.alert">European Single Procurement Document (ESPD) is a self-declaration of the businesses' financial status, abilities and suitability for a public procurement procedure. It is available in all EU languages and used as a preliminary evidence of fulfilment of the conditions required in public procurement procedures across the EU. Thanks to the ESPD, the tenderers no longer have to provide full documentary evidence and different forms previously used in the EU procurement, which means a significant simplification of access to cross-border tendering opportunities. From October 2018 onwards the ESPD shall be provided exclusively in an electronic form. The European Commission provides a free web service for the buyers, bidders and other parties interested in filling in the ESPD electronically. The online form can be filled in, printed and then sent to the buyer together with the rest of the bid. If the procedure is run electronically, the ESPD can be exported, stored and submitted electronically. The ESPD provided in a previous public procurement procedure can be reused as long as the information remains correct. Bidders may be excluded from the procedure or be subject to prosecution if the information in the ESPD is seriously misrepresented, withheld or cannot be complemented with supporting documents.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.create.espd">Create a new ESPD</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.create.response">Create response</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.header">Welcome to the ESPD service</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.i.am.ca">I am a contracting authority</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.i.am.ce">I am a contracting entity</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.i.am.eop">I am an economic operator</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.import.espd">Import ESPD</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.merge.espds">Merge two ESPDs</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.reuse.espd">Reuse an existing ESPD</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.review.espd">Review ESPD</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.select.country">Select country</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.ted.reception.id.placeholder">Please specify the received notice number</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.upload.document">Upload document</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.upload.documents">Upload documents</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.upload.request">Please upload an ESPD request from the contracting authority</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.upload.request.response">Please upload an ESPD Request or an ESPD Response</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.upload.response">Please upload an old ESPD response from you</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.what.you.do">What would you like to do?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.where.are.you.from.ca">Where is your authority located?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.where.are.you.from.eo">Where is your business located?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.who.are.you">Who are you?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.footer.last.update">Last Update:</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.grow">Growth</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.information.for.country">Information for {0} on e-Certis</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.legal.notice">Legal Notice</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.less.information">Less information</entry>
    <entry key="espd.ecertis.more.information">More information</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.next">Next</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.no">No</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.not.applicable">Not applicable</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.place">Place</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.previous">Previous</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.print">Overview</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.progress.exclusion">Exclusion</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.progress.finish">Finish</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.progress.procedure">Procedure</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.progress.selection">Selection</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.progress.start">Start</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.question.to.use.alpha">Do you want to use the selection criteria from A to D?</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.report.appliction.issue">For any issues related to the ESPD application please contact the</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.report.security.incident">Report on an Information Security Incident</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.report.security.incident.title">For any security incident please contact the European Commission through the</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.role.ca">Role: Contracting Authority (CA)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.role.eo">Role: Economic Operator (EO)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.search">Search</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.signature">Signature</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.tools">Tools</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.ca.can.create.espd.tooltip">The contracting authority can create an ESPD from scratch. In such a case, the contracting authority has to fill in the ESPD form with all relevant information.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.ca.can.import.espd.tooltip">If the contracting authority has already used the ESPD service for another procurement procedure in the past, it can import the ESPD stored on the local network. In this case, the ESPD does not have to be filled in from scratch but some data still needs to be updated to take into account the current procurement procedure.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.ca.ref.buyer.tooltip">The term contracting authority refers to the buyer.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.ce.ref.buyer.tooltip">The term contracting entity refers to the buyer.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.eo.can.reuse.espd.tooltip">The economic operator can reuse the information, which was provided via an ESPD in a previous procurement procedure ('old' ESPD). The ESPD service will merge the 'old' ESPD with the new form prepared by the contracting authority for this procurement procedure.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.eo.ref.suppl.tooltip">The term economic operator refers to the supplier / bidder.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.espd.used.both.ca.eo.tooltip">The ESPD service can be used by both contracting authorities and economic operators. Please select the option which corresponds to your profile in this public procurement procedure.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.filter.create.response.tooltip">Create a new ESPD Response</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.filter.eo.can.import.espd.tooltip">The economic operator can import the ESPD file, which was pre-filled by the contracting authority for this public procurement procedure and published with the tender notice.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.filter.eo.merge.espds.tooltip">The ESPD service will merge the 'old' ESPD with the new form prepared by the contracting authority for this procurement procedure.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.overview.received.espds.tooltip">This feature provides a table with an overview of answers included in all ESPDs provided by the bidders for a given procurement procedure.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.review.espd.tooltip">The contracting authority can check/review the electronic ESPD received from the economic operator.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.init.ted.reception.id.tooltip">The contracting authority will receive an e-mail from the publication office when they have submitted a notice for publication. This email contains an ID that can be used in this service to fill out information about the procedure and the authority.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.accept">Please enter a value with a valid extension.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.creditcard">Please enter a valid credit card number.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.date">Please enter a valid date.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.dateISO">Please enter a valid date (ISO).</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.digits">Please enter only digits.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.email">Please enter a valid e-mail address.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.equalTo">Please enter the same value again.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.max">Please enter a value less than or equal to {0}.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.maxlength">Please enter no more than {0} characters.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.min">Please enter a value greater than or equal to {0}.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.minlength">Please enter at least {0} characters.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.number">Please enter a valid number.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.range">Please enter a value between {0} and {1}.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.rangelength">Please enter a value between {0} and {1} characters long.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.remote">Please fix this field.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.required">This field is required.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.validator.url">Please enter a valid URL.</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.view.ca">View: (CA)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.view.eo">View: (EO)</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.yes">Yes</entry>
    <entry key="espd.gui.zip.instructions">This is a short documentation of the ESPD files that you find in this ZIP folder.Chr(92)Chr(92)rChr(92)nChr(92)rChr(92)nespd.XML: The XML file is a file that our ESPD service or other compatible ESPD services can understand. The advantage of using the eESPD as a XML file is that buyers and companies can reuse it for other procedures in the future. It should be sent together with the procurement documents (from authority to companies) or as part of the bid (company to authority).Chr(92)Chr(92)rChr(92)nChr(92)rChr(92)nespd.PDF: The PDF file is a human readable file of the eESPD. We suggest here as well that it is used alongside the XML format with the procurement documents (from authority to companies) or as part of the bid (company to authority) as a reference document.Chr(92)Chr(92)rChr(92)nChr(92)rChr(92)nIf you have questions about the files please do not hesitate to get in contact with us through the following email address: grow-espd@ec.europa.eu.</entry>
</properties>
